

Phone: +61 434390783 Email: sliu178@gmail.com Website: http://samliu.me github: github.com/bzsamus

OBJECTIVE

I am seeking a creative and challenging position in web development that utilize my skills and further expand my technical skills.

SUMMARY

A well rounded web developer with over five years of experience in analyzing, developing and managing websites and web applications. Constantly learning and self-directed with the ability to work independently and as part of a team.

My ability to research, analyze and solve problems with a great instinct, determination and business sense can be an instant benefit to your team or organization.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Languages: PHP, Python, Javascript, Objective C, HTML,

OOP, Design pattern

Database: MySQL, SQLite, MongoDB

Technologies & Tools: memcache, Codelgniter, Django, jQuery, smarty

Operating Systems: CentOS, FreeBSD, Windows, Mac OS

Web servers: Apache, lighttpd, nginx Data Mining: google analytic, kontagent

Version Control: Git, Mercurial

LANGUAGES

Fluent in English and Mandarin Chinese.

Phone: +61 434390783 Email: sliu178@gmail.com Website: http://samliu.me github: github.com/bzsamus

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Freelancer, Saturday LLC., Taipei, Taiwan — 2011~recent

- Audio-Technica Taiwan (http://www.audio-technica.com.tw/)
 Worked with another freelance designer and helped client redesign and develop website using PHP, MySQL, Javascript, jQuery.
- Jellybird Company (http://www.jellybirdcompany.com/)
 Understand client's requirement and provide solution within required timeframe and budget. Website developed using Wordpress for content management. Other pages are highly customized with facebook social plugin and open graph integration. SEO and analytic metrics.
- Tarot Yearcycle (http://itunes.apple.com/tw/app/ta-luo-liu-nian/id477137482?mt=8)
 Developed using native Objective C. Personal side project.

Software Developer, meeya Inc., Taipei, Taiwan — 2008~2011

- Worked in a team of 4 developers. My main responsibility is to develop new features for social website meeya.cc using PHP and MySQL.
- Worked with a project manager and a designer, we created a PHP, MySQL based web game called "island7" in 4 weeks and launched on social website meeya.cc.
- The company I worked for act as a production house for advertising agencies, providing digital marketing solutions on facebook. I worked as R&D for facebook API's, social channels and open graph protocol. I have also created a system that used MVC framework(codeigniter and django) to quickly generate applications on facebook by making commonly used features as modules.
- Worked as lead backend developer for facebook social game "StoreCity" https://apps.facebook.com/storecity_tw/. The team consist of 2 backend developer, 3 frontend flash developer, 1 hardware architect and 3 designer. My main role was to write backend core which requires me to collaborate closely with frontend developer and hardware architect. We used svn for version control and redmine for milestone planning and issue tracking. The backend was written in PHP and uses singleton, factory and adapter pattern. PHPUnit used for unit testing.
- Lead developer for social game "StoreCity" cross platform deployment. Collaborate remotely with engineers from Rekoo China and Plinga Germany to deploy the game on mixi Japan, mobage Japan, Hyves Nederlands and Nasza Klasa Poland using OpenSocial protocol.

Software Developer, CoreLight Technology Co., Ltd., Taipei, Taiwan — 2007~2008

- Worked as a junior developer. My main role was to maintain, bug fix and adding features to the exist LMS(Learning management system) platforms using PHP, MySQL and smarty.
- Implemented blog system & live broadcast channel into Shih Chien University Library website with another developer, using PHP and MySQL hosted windows NT server. The blog was done using Drupal and live broadcast as a module.

Phone: +61 434390783 Email: sliu178@gmail.com Website: http://samliu.me github: github.com/bzsamus

EDUCATION

University of Auckland, New Zealand — BSc, Computer Science 2001~2003

OTHER

- Participant of Yahoo! Open Hack Day Taiwan 2008
- Volunteer helper for Facebook Developer Garage Taipei 2009,2010